Full Stack Engineer

Đức Phương

Phone: +84 984 933 473 Email: dphuong2103@gmail.com Portfolio: https://midouz-portfolio.netlify.app

Seeking a job opportunity with a focus on Full Stack

Summary

• 3+ years experience in Software Development

· Objective: Become Software Engineer Specialist

Skills & Background Knowledge

Programming Languages	JavaScript & TypeScript, Java			
Tools	Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Linux, Docker, VPS			
Foreign Languages	English: Professional Working Proficiency, Japanese: very basic			
Frameworks, Libraries	FrontEnd: ReactJs, NextJs, Material UI, BootStrap, Redux, Zustand, Context			
	Provider, TailWind CSS, Shaden, GraphQL Client, Rest API			
	BackEnd: SpringBoot, GraphQL Server, Rest API			
	Database: MySQL, MS SQL Server, Firebase			
Others	Strong understanding of OOP methodologies and SOLID principles			
	Experience with Docker, Linux and VPS			
	Effective troubleshooting and problem-solving skills			
	Proficiency in designing and implementing responsive user interfaces			
	Capability to optimize application performance through best practices			
	Experience in collaborative work with backend developers to define API contracts			
	Outstanding communicating and presenting skills			

Projects

GLSOFT-FULLSTACK ENGINEER

JUN 2023 - NOW

EV CHARGER MANAGEMENT PROJECT

Responsibilities	Evaluate front-end technologies, make design decisions, and migrate legacy front-e			
	projects to newer technologies.			
	Collaborate with Business Analysts to gather requirements and provide consultancy.			
	Perform demonstrations to users after every sprint.			
	Design and implement responsive user interfaces using Next.js, TypeScript, and SCSS.			
	Optimize application performance through best coding and design practices.			
	Integrate GraphQL for efficient data fetching and state management.			
	Participate in code reviews to maintain high coding standards and share knowledge			
	within the team.			

	Troubleshoot and resolve issues to ensure application stability.			
	Manage Docker containers for development, testing, and production environments.			
	Work with backend developers to define and implement API contracts.			
Description	Develop and manage the Admin Page for charger management for electric vehicles in			
	Hong Kong and Thailand, including CRUD operations and analytics, reporting using			
	NextJs			
Technologies	Frontend: NextJs, TypeScript, SCSS, Bootstrap, Context Provider, GraphQL Client, Apex			
	chart, react-dnd			
	Backend: Spring boot (3.0.1), GraphQL Server, Redis, Java (17)			
	Backend: Spring boot (3.0.1), GraphQL Server, Redis, Java (17) Database: MySQL			

Personal Projects

BLOG MARCH 2023 – JUN 2023

Demo Link	https://blog.phuongtran.site/				
	Demo account: <u>user1@gmail.com</u> / password: 123456				
Git Hub	https://github.com/dphuong2103/blog				
Function	Implemented secure user authentication system with email and password, ensuring				
	data protection using JWT for session management.				
	Developed a robust sign-up feature with validation and error handling for seamless user				
	onboarding.				
	Designed and integrated a paginated blog listing, optimizing performance and user				
	experience for large data sets.				
	Engineered dynamic blog detail views, enabling users to access content-rich blog posts.				
	Built a blog creation tool supporting MDX format, allowing seamless integration of				
	Markdown with React components for enhanced content flexibility.				
	Implemented search functionality, providing users with fast and accurate content				
	retrieval.				
	Added a dark mode toggle, improving user experience with a customizable UI theme				
	option.				
	Response view for all devices				
Technologies	Frontend: NextJs, TypeScript, SCSS, Shadon, Tailwind				
	Backend: Spring boot				
	Database: MySQL				
	Deployment: Docker				

TIMELESS LOVE JAN 2023–MARCH 2023

CH Play	https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.midouz.timeless_love_app&hl=end			
	gl=US			
Git Hub	https://github.com/dphuong2103/TimelessLove			
Function	Available in English and Vietnamese			
	Get in a relationship with another user by relationship code			
	Create, update, and delete questions			
	Store answers of couples			
	Notify when a new user adds or answers a question			
Technologies	Flutter, Firebase			

COUNTDOWN JAN 2023-MARCH 2023

Demo	https://dphuong2103.github.io/CountdownTimer/			
Git Hub	https://github.com/dphuong2103/CountdownTimer			
Function	Simple countdown timer for setting timer and countdown will start.			
	Sound notification when the countdown finish			
	Responsive design			
Technologies	Javascript, scss, html			

Work Experience

Company	Position	Software	Time
GLSoft	FullStack Engineer	EV Charger management	Jun 2023 – Now
Honda VietNam	IT Support, Consultant	SAP SuccessFactors,	Jun 2020 - Jun 2023
		VnResource HRM	
VnResource	Project Engineer, Project Leader	VnResource HRM	Jun 2019 - Jun 2023

Education

University of Information Technology (UIT)

Degree of Engineer in Information Technology

Foreign Trade University (FTU)

The Bachelor of Business Administration